Finding Aid for the Pat And Lily Okura Papers LSC.2367
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 6: Japanese American Citizens League (JACL) files, 1934-2004
  - Research for publication - Satow Memorial Fund, 1982 (Box 139, Folder 1)
    This contains JACL in Quest of Justice: The History of the Japanese American Citizens League by Bill Hosokawa.
  - Research for publication - Satow Memorial Fund, 1981-1996 (Box 139, Folder 2-8)
    This contains materials on the Masao W. Satow Memorial Fund Project Committee for JACL Story.
  - Research for publication - Japanese American Research Project (JARP), 1974-1978 (Box 138, Folder 1-2)
    This contains Gene N. Levine and Darrel M. Montero files.
  - Research for publication - JARP, 1976 (Box 138, Folder 3-4)
    This contains Edna Bonacich and John Modell files.
  - Research for publication - Satow Memorial Fund, 1972-1982 (Box 138, Folder 5-6)
    This contains materials on the establishment of the Masao W. Satow Memorial Fund Project Committee.
  - Research for publication - JARP, 1963-1968 (Box 137, Folder 1-3)
    This was formerly initiated as Japanese American History Project.
  - Research for publication - JARP, 1969 (Box 137, Folder 4)
    This contains Nisei: The Quiet Americans by Bill Hosokawa.
  - Research for publication - JARP, 1974-1980 (Box 137, Folder 5)
    This contains Robert A. Wilson files.
  - Research for publication - JARP, 1980 (Box 137, Folder 6)
    This contains East to America: A History of the Japanese in the United States by Robert A. Wilson and Bill Hosokawa.
  - Research for publication - JARP, 1974-1975 (Box 137, Folder 7-8)
  - Redress National Committee, 1964-1998 (Box 136, Folder 1-7)
    This contains files on media depictions of Nisei and redress celebration of the Civil Liberties Act of 1988.
  - Youth, Career and Scholarships National Committee, 1960-2002 (Box 136, Folder 8-12)
  - Research for publication, 1960-1961 (Box 136, Folder 13)
    This contains History of the Japanese in America Project, 1860-1960 by Scott T. Miyakawa.
  - Redress National Committee, 1984-1988 (Box 135, Folder 1-9)
  - Redress National Committee, 1981-1984 (Box 134, Folder 1-6)
  - Redress National Committee, 1981-1982 (Box 133, Folder 1-6)
  - Redress National Committee, 1980-1982 (Box 132, Folder 1-4)
  - Legislative Education National Committee, 1983-1998 (Box 131, Folder 1-5)
    This contains files on lobbying. Folder 5 contains a Redress: the JACL Campaign for Justice VHS.
  - Redress National Committee, 1977-1984 (Box 131, Folder 6-8)
  - Legislative Education National Committee, 1986-1987 (Box 130, Folder 1-6)
    This contains files on lobbying.
  - International Relations National Committee, 1975-1991 (Box 129, Folder 1-8)
    This contains files on the Pan American Nikkei Association conferences and international festivals.
  - Legislative Education National Committee, 1981-1986 (Box 129, Folder 9-12)
  - International Relations National Committee, 1975-1999 (Box 128, Folder 1-8)
    This contains work files on U.S.-Japan relations.
  - Civil Rights National Committee, 1963-2001 (Box 127, Folder 1-6)
    This contains photographs from the 1963 March in Washington, D.C.
  - Curriculum Education National Committee, 1996-2002 (Box 127, Folder 7-10)
    This contains resource guides.
  - International Relations National Committee, 1967-1971 (Box 127, Folder 11-12)
    This contains files on national tours to Japan.
  - Awards and Recognitions National Committee, 1970-1990 (Box 126, Folder 1-12)
    This contains files on the JA of the Biennium award and testimonial tributes to Mike M. Masaoka, Saburo Kido, and Nikkei congress members.
  - Aging and Retirement National Committee, 1988-2000 (Box 125, Folder 1-7)
    This contains files on collaborative programs with the AARP.
  - Awards and Recognitions National Committee, 1976-1994 (Box 125, Folder 8-10)
    This contains files on the JA of the Biennium award. Folder 9 contains service ribbons.
  - Aging and Retirement National Committee, 1975-1989 (Box 124, Folder 1-9)
  - Aging and Retirement National Committee, 1979-1983 (Box 123, Folder 1-8)
    This contains files on Nisei retirement planning programs in conjunction with the AARP and Commission on Wartime Relocation and Internment of Civilians (CWRIC) testimony by Louise M. Kamikawa in Seattle. Folder 5 contains files on the Nisei Aging and Mental Health Project at the University of Washington.
  - Aging and Retirement National Committee, 1976-1979 (Box 122, Folder 1-9)
  - WDC Chapter community outreach, 1976-1996 (Box 121, Folder 1-3)
    This contains materials on the Keiro Kai Issei Senior Appreciation and Scholarships and Mochitsuki New Year festivals.
  - WDC Chapter Education Committee, 1975-2002 (Box 121, Folder 4-7)
  - Aging and Retirement National Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 121, Folder 8-9)
  - WDC Chapter Memorial Day services, 1992 (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - WDC Chapter community outreach, 1974-1992 (Box 120, Folder 2-10)
    This contains materials on the Aki no Ichi Japanese Autumn Festivals. Folders 2-5 contain materials on the first annual National APA Heritage Week.
  - WDC Chapter newsletter, 1984-2003 (Box 119, Folder 1-4)
  - WDC Chapter Memorial Day services, 1963-1980 (Box 119, Folder 5-8)
    This contains materials on the commemorative service at Arlington National Cemetery honoring JA military service in WWII.
  - WDC Chapter installations, 1995-1999 (Box 118, Folder 1-3)
  - WDC Chapter newsletter, 1964-1991 (Box 118, Folder 4-6)
  - WDC Chapter installations, 1988-1996 (Box 117, Folder 1-10)
  - WDC Chapter installations, 1977-1988 (Box 116, Folder 1-9)
  - WDC Chapter general records, 1967-1999 (Box 115, Folder 1-11)
    This contains membership records.
  - WDC Chapter general records, 1967-2004 (Box 114, Folder 1-15)
    This contains financial and membership records.
  - WDC Chapter general records, 1973-2002 (Box 113, Folder 1-9)
    This contains board meeting files and financial records.
  - WDC Chapter general records, 1992-1996 (Box 112, Folder 1-7)
    This contains board meeting files.
  - WDC Chapter general records, 1983-1991 (Box 111, Folder 1-7)
  - WDC Chapter general records, 1973-1987 (Box 110, Folder 1-8)
    This contains files on President Ben Watada and board meetings.
  - WDC Chapter general records, 1979-1994 (Box 109, Folder 1-8)
    This contains files on President Ben Watada.
  - Pacific Northwest chapters, 1964-1982 (Box 108, Folder 1)
  - WDC Chapter general records, 1971-1979 (Box 108, Folder 2-11)
  - Los Angeles and other chapters in California, 1934-1969 (Box 107, Folder 1-8)
    This contains a photograph of the national golf tournament in September 1939 at the Lakewood Country Club. Folders 2-4 contain photographs and programs of annual Nisei festivals from 1934-1938.
  - Midwest chapters, 1968-1992 (Box 107, Folder 9)
    This contains the What's in a Word? pamphlet by the Chicago Chapter.
  - Omaha, Nebraska Chapter, 1947-1997 (Box 107, Folder 10-16)
    Folder 18 contains photographs of Omaha chapter officers.
  - Eastern District Council, 1992-2003 (Box 106, Folder 1-6)
  - East Coast chapters, 1981-1993 (Box 106, Folder 7)
  - Eastern District Council, 1982-1991 (Box 105, Folder 1-7)
  - Eastern District Council, 1976-1982 (Box 104, Folder 1-7)
  - National Board Records, 1941-1973 (Box 103, Folder 11-12)
    This contains the JA Creed and National Headquarters Bulletin from 1944 and 1973.
  - National Council, 1992-2002 (Box 103, Folder 1-5)
  - Mountain Plains District Council, 1965 Nov 27 (Box 103, Folder 6)
    This contains a district council 9th biennial convention program.
  - District Council joint conventions, 1963 November (Box 103, Folder 7)
    This contains files on the Northern California-Western Nevada District Council meeting.
  - Omaha, Nebraska Chapter, 1954, 1960 (Box 103, Folder 8)
  - WDC Chapter general records, 1986 (Box 103, Folder 9)
  - Publications - organizational literature, undated (Box 103, Folder 10)
    This contains a Better Americans in a Greater America manuscript.
  - National Council, 1962-1990 (Box 102, Folder 1-10)
    This contains official minutes and reports.
  - Biennial National Conventions, 2000-2002 (Box 101, Folder 1-3)
  - Mountain Plains District Council, 1957-1997 (Box 101, Folder 4-9)
    Folder 9 contains a photograph by Tom Masamori of the Rocky Mountain Nisei War Memorial dedication at Fairmount Cemetery in Denver, CO.
  - District Council joint conventions, 1959-1999 (Box 101, Folder 10-11)
    This contains files on the regional conventions and Eastern-Mountain Plains district councils joint conventions.
  - Biennial National Conventions, 1984-1998 (Box 100, Folder 1-10)
  - K. Patrick Okura JACL Distinguished Achievement Award, 1952 (Box 224, Folder 4)
- Series 7: World War II experience files, 1941-1990
  The World War II experience files contain documentation of the forced removal, and incarceration of Japanese Americans during the war and documentation of post-war relocation, resettlement, the Redress Movement, and reparations. Materials include monitor lists of all trains departing from Santa Anita, train schedules to camps, Santa Anita Pacemaker newspapers, and incarceration files of the Okura and Arikawa families.
  - Forced removal, 1942 April-July (Box 141, Folder 1-3)
    This contains preparation, economic losses, and Japanese American Citizens League (JACL) reports on agricultural and economic impacts. Folder 3 contains stock photographs taken by the War Relocation Authority (WRA).
  - Forced removal - Santa Anita, 1942 April-September (Box 141, Folder 4-10)
    This contains stock photographs, Santa Anita Assembly Center administrative records, and self-government council work files. Folder 9 contains lists of community leaders, sectional representatives, and district councilmen. Folder 10 contains list of families scheduled for Poston, and charts outlining districts, sectionals, and units.
  - Forced removal, 1942 June 17 (Box 198, Folder 2)
    This contains framed WRA Evacuation of Restricted Areas government-issued checks.
  - Forced removal - monitor lists of all trains departing from Santa Anita, 1942 September-October (Box 141, Folder 11)
    This contains lists of train, pullman, and car monitors.
  - Forced removal - train schedules to Delta, Utah War Relocation Authority (WRA) camp, 1942 October (Box 141, Folder 12)
    This is also known as Topaz, or Central Utah. This contains materials on trains departing from Santa Anita, CA. Also contains passenger names, ID numbers, and addresses.
  - Forced removal - train schedules to Poston, Arizona WRA camp, 1942 August-October (Box 141, Folder 13)
    This is also known as the Colorado River. This contains materials on trains departing from Santa Anita, CA. Also contains passenger names, ID numbers, and addresses.
  - Forced removal - train schedules to Gila River WRA camp, 1942 October (Box 141, Folder 14)
    This contains materials on trains departing from Santa Anita, CA. Also contains passenger names, ID numbers, and addresses.
  - Forced removal - train schedules to Manzanar WRA camp, 1942 October (Box 141, Folder 15)
  - Forced removal - train schedules to Granada WRA camp, 1942 September-October (Box 142, Folder 1-2)
    This is also known as Amache. This contains materials on trains departing from Santa Anita, CA. Also contains passenger names, ID numbers, and addresses.
  - Forced removal - train schedules to Heart Mountain WRA camp, 1942 August-October (Box 142, Folder 3-4)
  - Forced removal - train schedules to Jerome WRA camp, 1942 September-October (Box 142, Folder 5-6)
  - Forced removal - train schedules to Rowher WRA camp, 1942 September-October (Box 142, Folder 7-8)
  - Forced removal - Santa Anita Pacemaker, 1942 April-October (Box 143, Folder 1-5)
  - Incarceration, 1942-1944 (Box 143, Folder 6-11)
    This contains publications from Jerome, Heart Mountain, and Tule Lake WRA Projects. Folder 6 contains WRA stock photographs of Granada Relocation Center.
  - Okura Family Incarceration, 1941-1944 (Box 143, Folder 12-13)
    This contains enemy alien papers, correspondence, and files of Momota Okura, and Okura family photographs during incarceration.
  - Arikawa Family Incarceration, 1942-1943 (Box 143, Folder 14-15)
    This contains enemy alien papers, correspondence, and files of Sadao and Masaye Arikawa.
  - Post-war Relocation and Resettlement, 1942-1952 (Box 144, Folder 1-13)
    This contains files, correspondence, and photographs of Japanese American relocation and resettlement efforts, especially in Omaha, NE. Folders 11-12 contain WRA stock photographs of incarcerees in Omaha.
  - Post-war Relocation and Resettlement, 1945 (Box 187, Folder 7)
    This contains Evening World Herald 1945 issues on the end of WWII.
  - Redress and Reparations, 1981 July 16 (Box 144, Folder 14)
    This contains Commission on Wartime Relocation and Internment of Civilians (CWRIC) testimony of Patrick Okura at a Washington, D.C. hearing.
  - Redress and Reparations, 1981 August 5 (Box 144, Folder 15)
    This contains CWRIC testimony of Sadao Arikawa presented by daughter Yayoi Ono at a hearing in Los Angeles, CA.
  - Redress and Reparations, 1982-1983 (Box 144, Folder 16)
    This contains the State of California reparations bill AB 2710 and redress.
  - Redress and Reparations, 1984-1985 (Box 144, Folder 17)
    This contains files on the City of Los Angeles redress.
  - Redress and Reparations, 1984 September 5 (Box 224, Folder 2)
    This contains the City of Los Angeles, State of California Resolution of apologies to Kiyoshi P. Okura and Japanese American employees during WWII which was adopted by the City Council and signed by Mayor Bradley.
  - Redress and Reparations, 1986 July 18 (Box 144, Folder 18)
    This contains correspondence with Aiko Herzig-Yoshinaga regarding Sadao Arikawa incarceration.
  - Redress and Reparations, 1988 December 13 (Box 144, Folder 19-20)
    This contains Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) records requested through the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) on K. Patrick Okura.
  - Redress and Reparations, 1990 October (Box 144, Folder 21)
    This contains formal letters of apology with restitution signed by U.S. President George H.W. Bush and received by K. Patrick and Lily Okura.
- Series 8: Personal record files, 1912-2009
  The Personal record files include appointment books, biographies, oral histories, published works, unpublished works, commendations, memorials, obituaries, and documentation of social activities, education, and family.
  CONTAINS UNPROCESSED DIGITAL AND AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Digital and audiovisual materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email spec-coll@library.ucla.edu.
  - Appointment books, 1939-1970 (Box 145, Folder 1-12)
  - Appointment books, 1971-1974 (Box 146, Folder 1-11)
  - Appointment books, 1974-1977 (Box 147, Folder 1-7)
  - Appointment books, 1977-1979 (Box 148, Folder 1-9)
  - Appointment books, 1979-1982 (Box 149, Folder 1-8)
  - Appointment books, 1982-1989 (Box 150, Folder 1-13)
  - Appointment books, 1990-1994 (Box 151, Folder 1-13)
  - Appointment books, 1995-1998 (Box 152, Folder 1-7)
  - Appointment books, 1995-2005 (Box 153, Folder 1-7)
  - Education - high school, 1923-1928 (Box 154, Folder 1-7)
    This contains yearbooks and sports photographs.
  - Education - University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA), 1928-1941 (Box 154, Folder 8-14)
    This contains undergraduate and graduate transcripts, commencement programs, and post-graduate course notes.
  - Education - UCLA, 1933 June 13 (Box 226, Folder 1)
    This contains a Bachelor of Arts in Letters and Science diploma on a permanent frame mount.
  - Education - UCLA, 1935 Feb 6 (Box 227, Folder 1)
    This contains a Masters of Arts in Psychology diploma on a permanent frame mount.
  - Social activities - basketball, 1929-1932 (Box 154, Folder 15)
    This contains photographs of the Japanese Bruin Club of UCLA team.
  - Social activities - baseball, 1930 (Box 154, Folder 16-17)
    This contains photographs of the Long Beach Nippons and Wanji teams.
  - Social activities - baseball, 1997-2001 (Box 155, Folder 1-2)
    This contains an undated photograph of K. Patrick Okura with his brothers and father in baseball uniforms, and participation in the Nisei Baseball Research Project.
  - Social activities - baseball, 1932 (Box 203, Folder 1)
    This contains a Wanji "A" League Champs ribbon pin presented to K. Patrick Okura by the Southern California Japanese Baseball Association.
  - Social activities - baseball, 1935 October 11 (Box 183, Folder 9)
    This contains a certificate to K. Patrick Okura of San Pedro as a member of the A League All Star Team 1930, by the Southern California Japanese Athletic Union, with sponsorship under the Los Angeles Recreation Department Board of Baseball.
  - Social activities - Kimekomi doll making, 1968-1999 (Box 155, Folder 3-7)
    This contains correspondence and photographs illustrating dolls crafted by Lily Okura and/or her students.
  - Social activities - Kimekomi doll making, 1985 (Box 202, Folder 1)
    This contains a certification of Lily Okura as a master teacher.
  - Social activities - golf, 1939-1981 (Box 155, Folder 8-11)
    This contains Washington Duffers Golf Club files. Folder 8 contains a L.B. Fairway Club group photograph at Montebello dated June 4, 1939.
  - Social activities - golf, 1984-1995 (Box 156, Folder 1-2)
    This contains Washington Duffers Golf Club files.
  - Social activities - Potomac Classic Thunderbird Club, 1979-2003 (Box 156, Folder 3-6)
  - Lily Arikawa family, 1916-1993 (Box 156, Folder 7-11)
    This contains Lily Okura's theater career, diary, and Arikawa family photographs.
  - Lily Arikawa family, undated (Box 186, Folder 9)
    This contains a portrait of Lily Okura in kimono.
  - Okura family - K. Patrick, 1912-2002 (Box 156, Folder 12-14)
    This contains photographs and portraits of K. Patrick Okura.
  - Okura family - K. Patrick, 1948 (Box 157, Folder 1)
    This contains photographs of a family gathering.
  - Okura family - K. Patrick, undated (Box 199, Folder 1)
    This contains K. Patrick Okura's business cards.
  - Okura family - K. Patrick, undated (Box 200, Folder 1)
  - Okura family - K. Patrick, undated (Box 201, Folder 1)
  - Okura family - James Momota, 1941-1995 (Box 157, Folder 2)
  - Okura family - Susumu Babe, 1944-1949 (Box 157, Folder 3)
  - Okura family - Susumu Babe, 1948 Aug 7 (Box 196, Folder 1)
    This contains a rolled panoramic photograph of Susumu "Babe" Okura and his 442nd color guard memorial ceremony at Evergreen Cemetery in Boyle Heights.
  - Okura family - Tomiko, 1943-1948 (Box 157, Folder 4)
  - Okura family - Tsuyoshi Tee, 1941-1959 (Box 157, Folder 5)
  - Okura family - Jimmy Mitsuru, undated (Box 157, Folder 6)
  - Okura family - Ben Tsutomu, undated (Box 157, Folder 7)
  - Okura family - K. Patrick and Lily, 1940-1990 (Box 157, Folder 8)
  - Okura family - K. Patrick and Lily, 1931-1952 (Box 157, Folder 9-13)
    This contains budget records.
  - Okura family - K. Patrick and Lily, 1952-1990 (Box 158, Folder 1-5)
    This contains a personal organizer, scrapbook, and materials on The Big Payoff television quiz show.
  - K. Patrick Okura obituaries and memorials, 2005 (Box 158, Folder 6-9)
  - K. Patrick Okura obituaries and memorials, 2005 March 10 (Box 183, Folder 8)
    This contains a tribute resolution in memoriam honoring K. Patrick Okura by the State of California Lieutenant Governor Cruz M. Bustamante.
  - Lily Arikawa Okura obituaries and memorials, 2005 (Box 158, Folder 10)
  - Obituaries and memorials of/for friends and colleagues, 1960-2004 (Box 158, Folder 11-14)
    This contains testimonials honoring Spark Matsunaga, Doris Hoshide, Toshio Hoshide, and Mike Masaoka.
  - Biographies and oral histories, 1999-2009 (Box 159, Folder 1-3)
    This contains a draft, manuscript, and final publication of Victory without Swords by Robert Kugel.
  - Biographies and oral histories, 1959-2002 (Box 159, Folder 4)
    This contains various articles and papers on K. Patrick and Lily Okura.
  - Biographies and oral histories, 1942-1990 (Box 187, Folder 4-6)
    This contains newspaper articles on K. Patrick and Lily Okura.
  - Biographies and oral histories, 1995 (Box 160, Folder 2-4)
    This contains transcripts of oral histories of K. Patrick and Lily Okura by the Japanese American Citizens League (JACL) Washington, D.C. Chapter Oral History Project. Folders 3-4 contain VHSs of oral history interviews.
  - Biographies and oral histories, 2003 (Box 160, Folder 5)
    This contains a Charter members, the Omaha story as told by K. Patrick Okura to Ellen Horiuchi Williams pamphlet, which was a gift from the JACL Washington, D.C. Chapter.
  - Biographies and oral histories, 1996-1999 (Box 160, Folder 6)
    This includes materials on Rita Takahashi.
  - Biographies and oral histories, 2004 June 8 (Box 160, Folder 7-8)
    Folder 8 contains a VHS of oral history interviews conducted by the Japanese American Veterans Association.
  - Commendations, 1936 (Box 203, Folder 2)
    This contains a District Winner Award ribbon for the Southern California Farm Oratorical Contest.
  - Commendations, 1940 March 15 (Box 161, Folder 1)
    This contains a Yamagata Award for Achievement, Nisei of the Year 1939 presented by the Japanese Young People's Association.
  - Commendations, 1940 March 15 (Box 203, Folder 3)
    This contains a Yamagata Award Pin for Achievement, Nisei of the Year 1939 presented by the Japanese Young People's Association.
  - Commendations, 1950-1989 (Box 183, Folder 10)
    This contains JACL Membership and Service commendations presented to K. Patrick Okura.
  - Commendations, 1952 (Box 183, Folder 11)
    This contains a JACL National Recognition Award for Distinguished Achievement in Science and Medicine presented to K. Patrick Okura.
  - Commendations, 1952 (Box 228, Folder 1)
  - Commendations, 1957 (Box 184, Folder 3)
    This contains an award plaque from the Nebraska Welfare Association.
  - Commendations, 1958-1962 (Box 183, Folder 12)
    This contains JACL Membership and Service commendations presented to Lily Okura.
  - Commendations, 1971 (Box 184, Folder 2)
    This contains an award plaque from Urban League of Nebraska.
  - Commendations, 1975 February 8 (Box 186, Folder 10)
    This contains an Asian Benevolent Corps Outstanding Government Service Award certificate.
  - Commendations, 1978 (Box 161, Folder 2)
    This contains a JACL Japanese American of the Biennium Award for K. Patrick Okura from 1976-1978.
  - Commendations, 1980 May 30-31 (Box 161, Folder 3-4)
    This contains a UCLA Alumni Association Award for Community Service to K. Patrick Okura.
  - Commendations, 1980 May 30-31 (Box 190, Folder 1)
    This contains a UCLA Alumni Association Commendation Award for Community Service plaque.
  - Commendations, 1980 May 30-31 (Box 190, Folder 2)
    This contains a UCLA Alumni Association Commendation Award for Community Service medallion.
  - Commendations, 1980 (Box 186, Folder 11)
    This contains a portrait of K. Patrick Okura with the UCLA Alumni Association Commendation Award for Community Service medallion taken by Olan Mills Studios.
  - Commendations, 1980 May 31 (Box 161, Folder 5)
    This contains materials on the Friends of Pat Dinner Reception for K. Patrick Okura hosted at General Lee's Man Jen Low restaurant, sponsored by Asian American (AA) community services organizations.
  - Commendations, 1980 May 31 (Box 225, Folder 1)